# PEDRO BUENO

 $\mathsf{CV}$ 

# **Mobile Developer**

Recife (PE) - Brazil

Telephone: +55 (81) 99872-8346 Email: <u>pedroarcbueno@gmail.com</u> Linkedin: <u>linkedin.com/in/arcbueno</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/arcbueno</u>

#### INTRODUCTION

Mobile Developer and fluent with Flutter, experienced with Android native (Kotlin), developing REST API with C# and scripting with Python and JavaScript. Have worked as a mobile team leader, choosing the app's architecture, state management, database, developing code documentation and helping team members. Have worked with Firebase libraries and SQLite, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Isar and Firestore databases.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **AMCom Information Systems**

#### Senior system developer - June 2023 ~ current

- Reponsive application development for iOS and Android
- Choosing app's archtecture, state management and main dependencies like GetX and RealmDB
- Main developer of mobile application team
- Requirement documentation
- · External APIs comunication analysis and
- Refactoring legacy code

#### **Neovero Systems**

## Mobile Developer - June 2019 ~ June 2023

- Mobile development team leader
- Mobile hybrid application development with flutter
- Android native application development with Kotlin
- API REST development with C# and Entity Framework
- Data management with SQLite and PostgreSQL
- Test planning, writing and execution

#### Champs.app

#### Flutter Developer - March/2023 ~ May/2023 - part-time

- Part-time job for USA company
- Function and components refactoring
- New features and pages development
- Creating and bug fixing on cloud functions with TypeScript
- Working with GCP and Firebase Firestore
- · Asynchronous communication with team members of Argentina and USA

#### **JoyStreet**

#### Flutter Specialist - July/2022 ~ August/2022 - freelancer

- Class material development of Flutter's course
- Flutter's documentation research and writing
- Small project development for helping students

#### CESAR - Center for studies and advanced systems in Recife

#### QA Intern - June/2018 ~ June/2019 - internship

- End-to-End test automation scripts development for Android with python
- Test plans execution and planning
- · Requirement study and analysis
- Test writing

#### **EDUCATION**

## Graduate Degree in Mobile Application Development - PUCPR | 2024 - ongoing

- Android and iOS Native development
- Hybrid Application development with Flutter
- UI/UX, Cloud Computing and IT Security

## Bachelor of Computer Science - UniFBV | 2016 - 2020

- Algorithms and data structure
- · Advanced programming
- Mobile application programming
- Database with SQLite, MySQL and Postgres
- Comparative research of Flutter and Android for mobile development

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Mobile: Flutter, Dart, Android Nativo e Kotlin
- Backend: C#, NodeJS
- Database: SQLite, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Realm, Isar, Firestore
- · Clean archtecture, Firebase auth, Firebase message, Unit tests
- Redux for Flutter, GetX, BLoC

#### **COURSES AND CERTIFICATES**

- Flutter: Stream's reactive programming with BLoC, Alura
- Flutter: Understanding HTTP communication and using with web APIs, Alura
- Flutter i18n: Learning internationalization approaches, Alura
- Flutter: State management with Provider, Alura
- Leadership: Learning about mission and the purpose of people leadership, Alura
- The Complete Flutter and Dart guide
- · Kotlin for Android
- NodeJs Essentials
- Automatic tests + Test software complete course

#### **LANGUAGES**

Portugueses: NativeEnglish: Advanced

#### **EXTRA**

US-Brazil Connect Program - 2015

• English conversation in weekly meetings